

DC ANALYST · ETL DEVELOPER

Jabalpur, Madhva Pradesh - 482005

□ (+91) 898-975-3843 | 🗷 deepjyotiroy079@gmail.com | 🖸 deepjyotiroy079 | 🛅 deepjyotiroy-079 | 💆 deepjyotiroy079

Summary.

3+ years of experience focused on ETL development and data warehousing. Currently working on SSIS, IICS, Microsoft SQL Server and AWS Redshift. Previously worked with Banking and Media/Entertainment Clients. Strong education professional with a Bachelor of Engineering degree focused on Information Technology.

Work Experience

Deloitte Consulting India Private Limited.

Kolkata, West Bengal

DC ANALYST

Jan. 2022 - present

- Engagement involves development of data flows based on the requirements of the stakeholders and the business needs. Also involved cross team coordination for on-time delivery of the process.
- Responsible for development of IICS and SSIS data flow for Tableau based dashboards.
- Adhering to timelines for delivery of required data / package.
- Developing **SQL queries** for collecting data for Tableau dashboards as required by the business.
- Working on **bug fixes** and **data correction/validation** for ADHOC requests created by the end users.

Hexaware Technologies

Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Dec. 2019 - Dec. 2021

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Adhering to timelines for **generating reports** for the financial organization.
- Responsible to loading data from source systems to data marts using star schema.
- · Participating in OS Patching and DB Patching Activity scheduled for the application and database servers.
- Scheduling and monitoring **Informatica Workflows** using **Autosys** tool.
- · Resolving incidents by collaborating with other technology teams and informing users about the same.
- Successfully Cleared Evolve Certification Gold Level for Data Integration Engineer

Education

Gyan Ganga Institute of Technology and Sciences

Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY (C.G.P.A:- 8.36)

Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2020

- Course work:- Computer Networking, Operating System, Object Oriented Programming and Methodology, Computer Architecture, Database Management System, Compiler Design, Artificial Intelligence, Cloud Computing, Programming in C, C++, C#, Java and Python.
- · Participated in several training conducted by the institute on Python, Machine Learning, LAMP Stack etc.
- Building major and minor projects during course work to understanding Software Development Life Cycle.

St. Gabriel's Senior Secondary School

Jabalpur, Madhya Pradesh

HIGHER SECONDARY - PCM (Percentage: - 75.2%)

Mar. 2015 - Mar. 2016

· Apart from the course work, participated in multiple inter school competitions and CBSE Cluster for Table Tennis.

Skills.

Software / Products Informatica PowerCenter, Oracle 12c, Apache Spark, DB2, SSIS, IICS, AWS Redshift

Operating System Microsoft Windows, Linux (Debian)

Language / Framework Python, Java, NodeJS, SQL, Express JS, REST APIs, Basics of CI/CD

Middleware / Database Oracle 12c, MySQL, Mongo DB, SQL Server, AWS Redshift

General Tools Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ, PyCharm, Git/Github, Jupyter Notebook, Docker

Acheivements

2019 Finalist, Smart India Hackathon - Software Edition

New Delhi

2019 **Finalist**, Jabalpur Hackfest - Smart City Hackathon

Jabalpur

Certifications

2020 Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, AZ - 900

2021 Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals, DP - 900

FEBRUARY 20, 2023 DEEPJYOTI ROY · RÉSUMÉ